混蛋
Jackass.
天呐
Aah! Ow! God!
你还好吧  C先生
Everything okay, Mr. C.?
你说呢  派
Does everything look okay, Pi?!
不好说  这儿有点暗啊
Uh, I don't know. It's kinda dark in here.
爸爸  你怎么了  出什么事了
Dad? Wh-what's going on? What happened?
立刻去我书房
My office. Now.
我已经尽量大度  体谅了
I've tried to be generous and understanding.
我已经很包容了
I have tried to be tolerant.
但是阿丽克西斯  这都一个多月了
But, Alexis, it's been over a month,
派居然还在这儿
and Pi is still here.
我知道
I know, dad.
他和我都挺不好意思的
And he feels bad about it. We both do.
我才不管他好不好意思
I don't care if he feels bad.
我要我的沙发
I want my couch back.
我要我的房子
I want my house back.
你下周就回大学了  到时候怎么办
You go back to college next week. What then?
亲爱的  他必须走人
Sweetheart, he has to go.
你说得对
You're absolutely right.
他的确待的太长了
He's been here way too long.
这不应该  对你不公平
It's not right, and it's not fair to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
好消息是  我们好像找到地方了
And the best news is, I think we found a place.
亲爱的  真是太棒了
Honey, that is so great.
你是说"我们找到地方了"吗
Did you say "We found a place"?
是啊  派和我谈过了
Yeah. Pi and I talked it over.
他自己租不起公寓
He can't afford a place on his own,
所以我们找到了一处合租
So we found one together.
-合租  -对
- Together? - Yeah.
这样我们都付得起房租
That way, the rent's totally affordable.
我的部分半工半读就能交得起
I can cover my half with a work-study job,
而且就在学校附近
and it's right next to school.
再说  这样你今年
Plus it'll save you having to pay
就不用付宿舍钱了
for university housing this year.
你不会真认为我会让你这么做吧
You don't honestly think I'm gonna let you do this, do you?
让我  爸爸  我都19了
Let me? Dad, I'm 19.
没错啊
Exactly my point.
年纪轻轻哪能就这么跟人同居
Far too young to be moving in with someone.
是吗  因为我已经到了可以签租约的年龄了
Really? Because I was old enough to sign the lease.
况且你19岁时不是也跟女友同居了吗
And weren't you living with your girlfriend when you were 19?
对  但那不一样
Yes. But that was different.
怎么不一样
How?
相信我  爸爸  我们都想清楚了
Trust me, dad. We've thought this through.
这绝对是正确的决定
It makes total sense.
这怎么能算正确的决定啊
In what universe does that make sense?
我告诉你吧
I'll tell you what universe--
她就是被感情蒙蔽了双眼  想不清楚
the one where she's blinded by emotion and not thinking straight.
简直想看慢动作的车祸
It's like watching a car accident in slow motion.
知道吗  卡塞尔  我爸爸想
You know, Castle, my dad wanted to kill
杀了我第一个同居男友
the first guy that I moved in with.
他想尽办法想劝我别那么做
He did everything he could to try and talk me out of it,
结果只让我更坚定了信心
and all that did was make me want to do it even more.
真希望未来的她
I wish her future self would come back
能来跟现在的她谈谈
and talk to her present self,
让她知道这是个大错误
let her know what a mistake she's making,
让她免遭
Save her from a...
伤害
a world of hurt.
怎么回事
What happened?
要我说  这世上就是有太多
A lot of weirdos out there with too much imagination
想象力太丰富的怪胎
is what happened.
没错  说的就是你  卡塞尔
And, yes, I'm looking at you, Castle.
但是我只在纸上犯罪
Yeah, except I only commit my murders on paper.
并不真正动手  票子多多  不蹲号子
I don't actually do them. A lot more lucrative, a lot less prison.
她受了电刑吗
So was she electrocuted?
对  但那不是死因
Yeah, but that's not the cause of death.
她被人割喉  还有这些
Her throat was cut. And the rest of this,
要我猜  她受了好一番刑呢
if I had to guess, I'd say she was tortured.
为什么  她是谁
Why? Who is she?
萨娜·泰勒  34岁
Shauna Taylor, 34.
惩治局的假释官
She's a parole office with the department of corrections.
或许是哪个假释犯的报复
Could be one of her parolees out for revenge.
-他怎么进来的  -暂时不知道
- How did he get in? - Right now it's a mystery.
没有强行闯入的迹象  并且看来
There's no sign of forced entry, and from the look of it,
她不知道有人要找她麻烦
she wasn't expecting trouble.
你怎么知道
How can you tell that?
她有个西格9的佩枪许可证
She had a carry permit for a sig .9.
枪还放在她床头柜的第一个抽屉里
Still in the top drawer of her nightstand.
我们知道死亡时间吗
Do we know when this happened?
得等回到验尸房才能给出定论
I won't have anything definitive until I get her back to the office.
邻居什么都没听到
Neighbors didn't hear anything,
大概是因为她被堵住了嘴
Probably because she was gagged.
报案的人说他看见
But the guy who called it in said that he saw
有人凌晨5点半离开了公寓
a guy leaving the apartment around 5:30 a.m.
而且他身上还沾了鲜血
Said the dude had fresh blood on him.
莱恩让证人跟素描师做描述了
Ryan's got our witness with the sketch artist now.
联系惩治局  拿到她所有假释犯的名单
Okay, contact D.O.C., get a list of all of her parolees,
看看有没有匹配记录
see if there's a match.
并让他们所有人给出昨晚的不在场证明
We're also gonna need alibis for all of them from last night.
对她家庭有什么了解
What do we know about her family?
她死了
She's dead?
我就知道
I knew it!
我就知道会发生这种事
I knew something like this would happen.
我早就说过了
I warned her, didn't I?
她热爱她的工作
She loved her job.
她喜欢帮助人们重拾生活
She loved helping people get their lives back on track.
威克福德博士  你和你继妹关系好吗
Dr. Wickfield, were you and your stepsister close?
不算是
Not really.
我们两个的生活轨迹很不同
The two of us had very different lives.
父亲死后  我们努力了
Since our father passed, we made an effort,
每个月也就给彼此打一两次电话
called each other once, maybe twice a month.
你上次跟她通话的时候
And when you last spoke to her,
她说过什么话  让你觉得她可能有麻烦吗
did she say anything that would indicate she was in trouble?
嗯  我们一周前通过话
Yeah. When we--we talked about a week ago.
她觉得可能有人在跟踪她
She said she thought someone might be stalking her.
她不论去哪都能看到一个人  盯着她看
She kept seeing this guy wherever she went, watching her.
是她的假释犯吗
One of her parolees?
不  她说她不认识他
No. She said she didn't recognize him.
我以为是她想多了呢
I thought maybe she was just being paranoid.
据萨娜的上司说
So according to Shauna's supervisor,
她的假释犯都不是暴力伤人犯
all of her parolees were nonviolent offenders,
而且也找不到跟邻居描述这副画像
and none of them looked like this sketch
相吻合的人
that we took off the neighbor
他们的指纹与鉴证组在犯罪现场采到的也不匹配
or match prints that C.S.U. got from the crime scene.
所以说可能这事跟她的工作毫无关系
So it's quite possible this had nothing to do with her job?
那何必给她上刑  凶手想要什么
Then why torture her? What could the killer want?
怎么  卡塞尔  没有疯狂理论吗
What, Castle, no crazy theories?
他有更烦的事要想呢
Oh, he's got bigger issues.
他女儿要跟一个男孩同居了
His daughter's moving in with a boy.
你居然不管吗
And you're letting her?
显然阻止她的唯一方法就是把她关起来
Well, apparently the only way to stop her is locking her up,
但据这位"遵纪守法"小姐说
but according to Miss by-the-book here,
那是非法监禁
that's unlawful imprisonment.
那个跟踪者有消息了
Hey. Caught a break on that stalker.
几晚前  萨娜提起了 一次骚扰投诉
Couple nights ago, Shauna filed a harassment complaint.
三天前  有人在萨娜下班回家的路上
Apparently, three days ago, a guy confronted Shauna
拦住了她
on her way home from work.
跟她说地球上一半的人危在旦夕
Said the lives of half the people on the planet were at stake.
不管我能想出什么疯狂理论
Whatever crazy theory I could have come up with,
都不如这个
this is better.
她想办法脱身并躲进了楼里
She managed to get away and duck inside her building,
但当她望向窗外时
but when she looked out her window,
他还在外面等着她  于是她报警了
he was still out there waiting for her, so she called the cops.
-他们把他抓起来了吗  -对
- Did they pick him up? - Yeah.
他没有身份证  而且他表现很奇怪
He didn't have an I.D. And he was pretty much off his rocker,
所以他们对他进行了72小时的精神病拘留
so they put him on a 72-hour psych hold.
他今天一大早被放走了
He was released early this morning.
他们一直没查到他的身份  但看看这个
They were never able to I.D. him, but check it out.
到精神科病房去  把他的记录拿来
Get over to the psych ward. Pull his records.
我们得查出他是谁
We need to find out who he is.
你不明白  我们就要没时间了
You do not understand. We are running out of time.
我得出去  你得放我出去
I need to get out of here. You have to let me go!
-你为什么要出去  -拜托  我告诉过你
- Why do you feel you need to go? - Come on, I told you!
-我  她有危险  -谁有危险
- I--she is in danger! - Who is in danger?
你根本就没有听我说话  萨娜·泰勒
You're not even listening to me! Shauna Taylor!
我只知道12-58  他们只告诉我这么多
All I know is 12-58. That is all they told me, okay?
事情就是那样开始的  如果我不去阻止
That is how is starts, and if I am not there to stop it,
我们都得死
we are all dead!
你听懂了吗  都得死
Do you understand me? Dead!
你...
You...
赶紧让我离开这儿
Somebody has to let me out of here!
听我说  我得去救她
All right, listen to me! I need to save her!
你觉得他说的救是杀的意思吗
Do you think by "save," he meant kill?
因为我觉得他听起来真的不想让她死
Because it sounds to me like he really didn't want her to die.
他有精神病
He's mentally ill.
他也许不知道区别
He may not know the difference.
12-58  你觉得那是什么意思
12-58--what do you think that means?
时间  地址  圣经章节
Time. Address. Bible verse.
又或许是...
Or maybe it's...
错乱的脑子里产生的随机数
Random numbers from a disturbed mind.
不管怎样  我们得找到他
Either way, we got to find him.
那家伙是个无名氏  没有身份  没有地址
The guy's a John Doe. He's got no I.D., no address.
可能是流浪汉  我们该从哪开始找
Could be homeless. Where do we even start?
我们要发一份全境通告  把他的信息发给
We'll put out a B.O.L.O., get his info
城里每家医院  每个分局  每家精神病院
to every hospital, precinct, and psych ward in the city.
我把他的照片发给庇护所
I'll send out his pictures to shelters
和施粥所  看看我们够不够走运
and soup kitchens, see if we can get lucky.
我想我们走运了
I think we just did.
刚刚是我们的被害人的邻居
That was our victim's neighbor.
他刚刚看到我们要找的无名氏
He just saw our John Doe
闯进了萨娜的公寓
breaking back into Shauna's apartment.
纽约警局  把手举起来
N.Y.P.D.! Show us your hands right now!
不
No!
不  放开我  你们不知道自己在做什么
No, no, no! Let me go! You don't know what you're doing!
我们很清楚自己在做什么
We know exactly what we're doing.
请听我说  别这样  拜托
Please listen to me. Don't do this. Please.
你们得让我走
You have to let me go.
如果不让我走  有十亿人得死
If you don't, a billion people will die.
-是嘛  他们要怎么死  -我不知道
- Yeah? How they gonna die? - I don't know.
我只知道他们要死了
I only know that they do.
是嘛  你怎么知道的
Yeah? How's that?
因为  我来自未来
Because... i'm from the future.
这成了我最喜欢的案子
This just became my favorite case.
那么...来自未来  对吧
So... future, huh?
-是的  -好吧
- That's right. - Okay.
我们从简单的开始吧
So why don't we just start with something simple,
比如你的名字
like your name?
为什么每个人都想知道我的名字
Why does everybody wanna know my name?
谁在乎呢  名字无所谓
And who cares? It doesn't matter.
-就当是为了我  -好吧
- Humor me. - Fine.
你可以叫我  西蒙  西蒙·道尔
You can call me... Simon. Simon... Doyle.
你到底是从哪年来的
And what year are you from, exactly?
-2035年  -卡塞尔
- 2035. - Castle.
别跟我说你不想知道
Don't tell me you weren't wondering.
不  我真正想知道的是
No, what I was actually wondering was
你在萨娜·泰勒的公寓里做什么
what were you doing in Shauna Taylor's apartment?
跟你们一样  寻找杀她的凶手
Same thing you were, I expect. Looking for her killer.
但所有的证据都指向你
Except all the evidence points to you.
警探  防止她被杀是我的工作
Detective, it was my job to prevent her murder.
照此事实  证明完毕  我不是杀她的凶手
Ipso facto, Q.E.D., I am not her killer.
事实上  她根本就不应该死
Point, in fact, she was never even supposed to die.
好吗  但因为她死了
Okay? But because she has,
一连串的事件就开始了  如果我不阻止
a chain of events has started, that if I do not stop--
数十亿人都要死吗
Billions of people will die?
完全正确  听着...
That's exactly right. Look...
在2031年的能源战争之后
After the bloody energy wars of 2031,
我们终于发掘出了新型能源
we'd finally managed to cultivate new sources of power.
能源战争
Energy wars?
对  新法西斯分子崛起
Yeah, neo-fascists come to power,
想以几个人的力量控制整个世界的
try to control the world's energy supply
能源供应  不过别担心  我们打败他们了
for a select few, but don't worry. We defeat them.
结果其中一个能量来源是个
Turns out that one of these new sources of power
超光速粒子加速器  它...
is a tachyon generator. It...
为我们打开了时间流的大门
Lets us open doors in the time stream continuum,
让我们能够回到过去
allowing us to travel back in time.
但为了防止被滥用
But, of course, because of the possibility of abuse,
它被严格控制并不为公众所知
It was tightly regulated and kept secret from the public.
我们有一个目击证人
We have a witness that saw you
看到你在萨娜·泰勒遇害不久后
leaving Shauna Taylor's apartment
离开她公寓
shortly after she was killed.
我就要说到那儿了  我是个时间人类学家
I'm getting to that. Look. Look, I'm a temporal anthropologist.
我们的工作是回到过去
What we do is we travel back in time
然后我们研究具有文化意义的时代
and we--and we study culturally significant eras--
古埃及  中世纪  伙计  我去过纳粹德国
Ancient Egypt, Middle Ages. Man, I've been to Nazi Germany.
你们不担心蝴蝶效应吗
Aren't you worried about the butterfly effect?
不小心改变了过去的某些东西
Accidentally changing something in the past,
以至于改变了未来
thus altering the future?
不  我们很小心
No. We're careful.
时间流基本是可以自我修正的
The time stream is mostly self-correcting, okay?
那些小的变化就像是流速很快的
Any small change is like a little ripple
河流中的小波浪  对吧
in a fast-moving river, right?
很快就消失了  没关系的
It's gone in a second. Doesn't matter.
但如果有人要做什么大事
But if someone was to do something big,
如果有人要做非常大的事
if somebody was to do something massive,
那当然  你肯定是可以改变未来的
then, yes, of course, damn right you can change the future,
而且刚刚就发生了这样的事
and by the way, that's exactly what just happened.
有人闯进了我们的实验室
Somebody broke into our lab, okay?
未经允许就回到了过去  我们不知道是谁
Made an unauthorized jump back in time. We don't know who.
但他们这么做的时候  数字就会剧增
But when they did, the numbers-- they started to spike.
现在我就像是海啸来临前的潮水
Now I'm like a tide going out before a tsunami.
那海啸真来的时候呢
And what happens when the tsunami hits?
暂时还没赶上我们  不过等它真来了
Well, it hasn't caught up to us yet, okay, but when it does,
不管现在发生的事启动了什么事件链
Whatever chain of events that has just started now will result
都会导致数十亿人无辜丧命
In billions of deaths that did not otherwise occur.
明白我的意思吗
You understand me?
好吧  道尔先生  就算你真的
Okay. Um, Mr. Doyle, let's say that you are indeed
来自未来
from the future...
萨娜·泰勒是怎么卷进这些事中的
How did Shauna Taylor fit into all of this?
为什么她的死能从根本上改变一切
I mean, how does her death change things so radically?
我不知道  我只知道
I don't know. All I know is that
我们从时间线上第一个改变点追踪到了她的公寓
We traced the first change in the timeline to her apartment,
10月7日  上午12:58
October 7th, 12:58 a.m.
所以他们才派你回来  所以你才会跟她搭讪
Which is why they sent you back, why you accosted her...
你是为了阻止连锁事件开始
To stop that first event.
我失败了  好吧  现在她已经死了
And I failed, okay? And now she's dead.
可这也是我翻她公寓的原因
But this is why I was searching her apartment--
我是想找出她为什么被锁定为目标
To find out why she was targeted,
为什么这人要折磨她
Why this person would torture her.
他穿越时空回来找她一定有原因
There's a reason he came back in time to find her.
她有他要的东西
She had something he needed.
我不知道是什么  某些信息  无关紧要了
I don't know what. Some piece of information. Doesn't matter.
重要的是我得离开这里  明白吗
What matters is that I get out of here, okay?
现在还不晚
Because it is not too late.
我还是可以阻止一切
I can still stop this.
但你们得马上放我走  明白吗
But you have to let me go now, okay?
在他们召回我之前  我只有几小时时间了
I only have a few hours before they recall me.
你就准备好延误吧
You're gonna be delayed.
不是吧
Oh, no.
召回你
Recall you?
太痛苦了  我简直在跟原始人说话
This is painful. No, man. I'm talking to people
这些人甚至还以为地球是方的
who still think the earth is flat.
他的指纹
His fingerprints are a match
跟我们从犯罪现场提取到的相吻合
for the ones we pulled from the crime scene.
毫无疑问  他就是凶手
No question he's our guy.
是的  毫无疑问
Yeah. No kidding.
-你犯大错了  -卡塞尔
- You're making a huge mistake!  - Castle.
-怎么  -考虑到咱俩的将来
- Yeah?  - For the sake of our future,
拜托你告诉我你不相信那家伙
Please tell me you don't believe that guy.
-我不信  但你得承认这是个好故事  -是吗
- Oh, no. But you got to admit, it's a great story.  - Really?
我倒觉得这是盗版捏造的
Uh, thought it was kinda derivative.
没错  像是《十二猴子》混搭《终结者》
Yeah, like a mash-up of "12 monkeys" and "Terminator."
是没错  可他讲故事的语气  相当投入啊
Yeah, but it's the way he told it...total commitment.
投入得都致命了
Commitment that turned deadly.
就为了维系他的想象
I mean, to maintain his delusion,
萨娜连命都丢了  他可能都不知道自己杀了她
Shauna had to die. He might not even know that he killed her.
你们查清道尔带的这设备
Hey, did you guys find out what this device was
是什么了吗
Doyle had on him?
科技处说这就是把垃圾零件组装到了一起的破烂
Tech said it's just a bunch of junk thrown together.
不然你以为是什么  卡塞尔
What were you expecting, Castle?
穿越时空的设备吗  神秘博士的音速起子吗
Time travel device? Doctor Who's sonic screwdriver?
你也看《神秘博士》啊
You watch "Doctor Who"?
是蕾妮  好了  我们去验尸房
Oh, that's Lanie. Okay, we'll hit the morgue.
你俩不如时空穿梭到自己的座位去吧
Why don't you guys time travel over to your desks
告诉地方检察官  我们抓到凶手了
and let the D.A. Know that we've got our killer?
他不是凶手
He's not your killer.
什么意思
What do you mean?
意思是  死亡时间是午夜到凌晨两点之间
I mean time of death was between midnight and 2:00 a.M.
而道尔被精神病拘留到四点才被释放
Doyle wasn't released from psychiatric hold until 4:00 a.M.
-不可能是他  -不  只能是他
- It can't be him.  - No, it has to be him.
他一直在跟踪她  而且他也在犯罪现场
He was stalking her, and he was at the crime scene.
没错  是她死后几小时后才去的
Yeah... hours after she was dead.
说实话  死亡时间很可能是凌晨一点左右
In fact, time of death is probably closer to 1:00 a.m.
-你怎么知道  -她的手表
- How can you tell that?  - Her watch.
指针停在12:58
It stopped at 12:58,
很可能是其中一次电击造成的
Probably from one of the electric shocks.
我能看看吗  12-58
May I? 12:58.
你起鸡皮疙瘩了吗
Did you just get a chill?
没有  卡塞尔  我没起鸡皮疙瘩
No, Castle, I didn't just get a chill.
想知道为什么吗
Do you wanna know why?
因为道尔就在犯罪现场
Because Doyle was at that crime scene,
他有大把时间去调她的手表
And he had plenty of time to change her watch
好跟他幻想出的故事相吻合
to fit his delusional story.
虽然她被杀时他不在现场
And just because he wasn't there when she was being murdered,
也不能说明他与这事完全没关系
it doesn't mean he's not involved somehow.
还有
There's something else.
萨娜遇害当晚曾跟什么人在一起过
Shauna was with someone the night she was killed.
当我把尸体上的血迹清洗干净后
Once I cleaned the blood from the body,
我看到了这些
I saw these...
在她脖子上
on her neck.
是唇膏吗
Is that lipstick?
跟她在一起的是个女人
She was with a woman.
伙计们  萨娜的继兄证实了
You guys, Shauna's stepbrother confirms
她是同性恋  但他确信她没有女友
She was gay, but he's sure she wasn't seeing someone.
她的手机记录里
There's nothing in her phone records
看不出有哪个联系人是女友
that would indicate a girlfriend.
不过  我发现了她遇害当晚的
However, I did find a charge to her credit card
一笔信用卡账单
for the night that she died.
乔治娅酒吧
Georgia's Bar.
就在她公寓楼下的转角附近
It's right around the corner from her apartment.
看起来她还给别人买了酒
Looks like she was buying for two.
可能是凶手
Could be our killer.
你俩过去看看
Okay, you guys get over there,
看有没有人看到她跟谁一起
see if she was seen with anyone
或者有没有人发现什么不寻常的地方
or noticed anything out of the ordinary.
我会打给地方检察官
I will call the D.A.
如果我们不能告道尔谋杀
If we can't charge Doyle with murder...
也许我可以给他申请精神病评估  暂时拘留他
Maybe I can get him held with a departmental psych eval
直到我们找出答案为止
until we have some answers.
没错  萨娜来过
Yeah, Shauna was here.
怎么了  她出什么事了吗
Why? Did something happen to her?
那晚她有跟谁一起吗
Was she with anyone that night?
有  挺奇怪的
Yeah. It was odd.
跟她一起那女的是个鸡
The chick she was hanging with was a pro.
-你是说妓女  -没错
- You mean, like, a hooker?  - Yeah.
我周末的时候在斯坦迪什的酒吧当酒保
I bartend weekends down at the Standish.
那女的是那边贵宾厅的常客
Chick's a regular in their lounge
目标都是高消费人士
targeting upscale men.
你以前见过她来这里吗
You ever seen her down here before?
我不知道她在工作还是怎么的
I don't know if she was working or what,
反正她跟萨娜看起来打得火热
but she and Shauna seemed pretty cozy.
而且她们是一起走的
They left together.
你知道她的名字吗
You know her name?
维罗妮卡  去斯坦迪什查查吧
Veronica. Go up to the Standish.
没人不知道她
She'll be hard to miss.
你们的证人弄错了
Your witnesses are confused.
我不去乔治娅那边  那可不够我的档次
I don't go to Georgia's. Not my scene.
我们有监控录像显示
Well, we have security camera footage
你们俩是一起离开那里的
that shows the two of you leaving there together.
要不要换个说法
Wanna try again?
好吧  我跟她离开了  想换个地方
Okay. I left with her. I like a little variety.
你离开酒吧之后发生了什么
And what happened after you left the bar?
-你去她家了吗  -这关你什么事
- Did you go to her place? - How is that your business?
因为...
Because...
她死了
she's dead.
昨晚在公寓里被杀
Killed in her apartment last night.
她脖子上有口红印
We found lipstick marks on her neck.
你觉得我们检验之后  会发现谁的DNA呢
When we test 'em, whose D.N.A. do you think we're gonna find?
不是我干的
This wasn't me. I didn't do this.
可是那晚你跟她在一起
You were with her that night.
只是因为有人付我钱
But only because I was paid to be.
-谁  -有个男人花钱雇我跟她搭讪
- By who? - Some guy. He hired me to come on to her.
-为什么  -他要我去她家  偷她的钥匙
- Why? - He wanted me to get in her place and steal her keys.
我不知道他会杀她
I-I didn't know he was gonna kill her.
是这个人吗
Is this the guy?
不  那个人很凶  很可怕
No. This guy was way more intense, scary.
-他是谁  -我不知道  我也不想知道
- Who is he? - I don't know. I didn't want to know.
我做了该做的  就离开了那里
I just did what I had to and I got out of there.
如果你不认识他  为什么要同意这样做
If you didn't know him, why'd you agree to take the job?
我别无选择  我的老板米克说我必须这样做
Because I had no choice. Mick, my manager, said I had to.
他说这个男人是他的朋友
He said this guy was a friend of his.
如果想找到这个可怕的男人
So if we are gonna find the scary guy,
难道不应该去找这位老板吗
shouldn't we be tracking down this manager?
没必要  我们让维罗妮卡给他打电话
Don't have to. We had Veronica call him
说她接活被被抓了
and tell him she's been busted for solicitation.
他以为来警局是为保释她
He thinks he's coming in to bail her out.
所以  那位时空穿梭者如何了
So... how's our time traveler?
他还是那套说法
Well, he's still sticking to his story.
一直在看手表  说马上要被召回了
Keeps checking his watch, saying he's about to be recalled.
不过这事也不算浪费
Hmm. Well, it's not a total waste.
我可是获得了第一手股票信息
I did get some excellent stock tips.
先别急着投资
Well, don't invest just yet.
只要搞清楚维罗妮卡的老板是谁
Once we find out who hired Veronica,
就知道道尔在其中扮演的角色了
then we'll know how Doyle's involved.
贝克特探长  我是谢夫曼医生
Detective Beckett? Dr. Silverman,
来做西蒙·道尔的精神评估
here for psych eval on Simon Doyle.
他就在里面
He's right back there.
在哪里
Right back where?
他在哪
Where is he?
他去什么地方了
Where did he go?
不是地方
Not where.
是什么时间
When.
我就是说  如果他说的是实话
I'm just saying, what if he was telling the truth
也许他确实被召回到未来了
and he really was recalled back to the future?
他不可能被召回到未来
He wasn't recalled back to the future.
你知道我怎么知道的吗
And do you know how I know that?
因为他不是时空穿梭者
Because he's not a time traveler.
好吧  那他在哪里
Okay. So where is he?
简单地说
Simple explanation?
取消对他的指控时
There was a mix-up with the paperwork
文件出了小错误
when his charges were dropped,
某个工作人员不小心放他走了
and some desk monkey accidentally let him go,
现在这个人正在试图掩盖自己的错误
and now they are all trying to cover their asses.
这解释很合理
That's reasonable.
虽然不太可能  但是很合理
It's unlikely, but it's reasonable.
道尔找得怎么样了
Oh. Any luck finding Doyle?
还没找到
No. Not yet. Hmm.
那是维罗妮卡的老板吗
Is that Veronica's manager?
对  米克·林登  刚来
Yeah. Mick Linden. Just came in.
我们打算让他见识我们的厉害
We're about to lower the boom.
需要帮忙吗
You need a hand?
不用  我们搞得定
Nah. We got it.
我们可不想让你把他也弄丢了
Wouldn't want you to lose him, too.
给你讲一下情况  米克
Here's your situation, Mick.
维罗妮卡声称
Your girl Veronica says she stole
她为了你朋友 偷了被害人的钥匙
the victim's keys for a friend of yours.
这样你成了从犯
That makes you an accessory.
天呐  我发誓...
Oh, man, I swear to god--
我不知道他会这样做
I-I didn't know he was gonna do this.
你觉得陪审团会相信你的说辞吗
Yeah, well, good luck getting a jury to buy that.
林登先生  这罪名可不小
You're looking at a lot of time, Mr. Linden.
别这样  我六个月前刚放出来
Come on, man. Hey, man, I just got out six months ago.
不如这样吧  你告诉我们
I'll tell you what. You tell us everything
你那个谋杀犯朋友是谁
about that murderous friend of yours,
我们就告诉地方检察院  你协助了调查
and we'll tell the D.A. what a swell guy you are.
他姓沃德  加瑞特·沃德
His name's Ward. Garrett Ward.
在五点监狱是我的狱友
Oh, my god. He was my cellie at Five Points.
哪里可以找到他
Where can we find him?
我不知道  上周是他找的我
I don't know, man. He found me last week.
说他刚放出来  需要我帮忙
Said he'd just gotten out, he needed a favor.
我觉得帮他总比跟他结仇好
I figured it was better to do it than end up on his hate list.
你害怕他
You're afraid of him.
废话  大家都怕他
Hell, yeah. Everyone was.
这人入狱一周
I mean, this guy was inside a week,
就混成了监狱老大
he was running the cell block.
残忍无比
Guy is ice-cold.
你还知道他什么事
What else do you know about him?
不知道
Nothing, man.
虽然我跟他一起住了好几年
And I shared air with this guy for years.
从来没谈过他的家人
Never once did he talk about his family,
没谈过家乡  女人
His hometown, his girl.
他可能当过兵
But he might have been a soldier.
怎么这么说
Yeah, why's that?
因为他有军人的不安全感
'Cause he had that way. Haunted.
老是在做俯卧撑  随时保持警戒
Always doing push-ups. Always on alert.
你知道他为何要对萨娜·泰勒下杀手吗
You know any reason why he'd target Shauna Taylor?
他根本没提过这个名字
He never even mentioned the name.
而且  你也说过  她不是他的假释官
And... you said before, she wasn't his parole officer,
所以我真不知道
so I have no idea.
也许他是为了帮朋友报仇
Could he have taken her out as a favor to a friend?
他根本没有朋友
That guy didn't have friends.
不过...
But, uh...
他有时会提到他的任务
like, sometimes he'd talk about his mission.
什么任务
What mission?
他只是说有未完成的任务
All he'd say is he had unfinished business,
说那会改变一切
and it would change everything.
加瑞特·沃德  六年前
Garrett Ward. Till six years ago,
没有犯罪记录
no criminal record.
事实上  六年前  他什么记录都没有
In fact, until six years ago, no record at all.
车管所  军队  哪里都没记录
No D.M.V., no military, nothing.
怎么可能
That's impossible.
除非他是道尔所说的
Unless he's the other time traveler
另一名时空穿梭者
that Doyle was talking about.
不管他是谁  他的记录始于
Whoever he is, his record begins
曼哈顿的一次国际能源会议
when he was arrested for bringing a backpack bomb
他因背包里携带了炸弹而被捕
into a Global Energy Conference here in Manhattan.
-什么动机  -当时
- And what was his motive? - Well, at the time,
当地政府称他与一个激进环保组织有关
the authorities linked him to a radical eco group
他们一直在抗议这场会议
that was protesting the conference.
这份文件显示
According to his file,
他似乎是个反科学研究的疯子
he's some kind of anti-science nut job.
他们在他身上发现许多炸弹客风格的笔记
They found lots of unabomber-style notebooks on him
谴责"用科学和技术毁灭
Decrying "The destruction of the rightful kingdom of god
上帝之国"
by science and technology."
-他和道尔有什么联系吗  -没有
- What's his connection to Doyle? - Nada.
怎么会没有  拜托伙计们  很明显好不好
What do you mean, nada? Guys, come on, it's so obvious!
你们看  沃德就是道尔
Look. Ward is the guy that Doyle
被派回来阻止的那个人
was sent back in time to stop, okay?
沃德被送回
Ward was sent back in time
完成某项改变历史的任务
on some history-altering mission
他任务失败  结果进了监狱
That he failed to accomplish, ending up in prison.
六年之后  他试图完成任务
Six years later, he's trying to complete that mission,
所以道尔被送回到现今
Which is why Doyle has been sent back to now,
因为现今时间线发生了改变
Because now is when the timeline changed.
我在想也许
Well, I was thinking that maybe
沃德和道尔在一个正常的世界认识对方
Ward and Doyle knew each other in the non-crazy world,
比如那个据称沃德是其中一员的环保组织
like perhaps that eco group that Ward was supposedly a part of.
好吧  真没趣
Okay. Not as fun.
但为什么一个反科学的狂热份子
But why would an anti-science nut
折磨并谋杀一位假释官呢
torture and murder a parole officer?
她和这些事情有什么联系
I mean, what's her connection to any of this?
我们还没找到
We still haven't found one.
你俩"回到过去"
Why don't you guys go back in time
看看能不能找到
and see if you can dig up
六年前沃德的已知合伙人
any of Ward's known associates from six years ago?
卡塞尔和我去研究他的案件记录
Castle and I will look into his case record,
看能不能找到他和萨娜·泰勒之间的联系
See if we can find a connection between him and Shauna Taylor
或是弄清楚他未完成的任务是什么
or perhaps figure out what his unfinished business was.
不  阿莱克西斯  我当然相信你
No, Alexis, I do trust you.
我是说  和一个在香蕉种植园
I'm just saying, deciding to share an apartment
认识才一个月的人同居
with someone you met on a banana plantation a month ago
不像是你做出的最明智的决定
just doesn't strike me as the smartest decision you've ever made.
阿莱克西斯  你--
Alexis, you--
阿莱克西斯--
Alexis--
她挂我电话
She hung up on me.
也许我不该提香蕉这茬
Maybe I shouldn't have said that stuff about the bananas.
你知道吗  卡塞尔
You know, Castle,
也许这对她来说是好事
maybe this is a good thing for her.
我是说  她看到我们在一起
I mean, she sees us,
她看到你开始了新的生活
and she sees you starting something new.
也许她是在努力弄明白怎么去适应
Maybe she's just trying to figure out how she fits in.
你是说这一切是因为我们
You're saying this is about us?
不是  我是说这是关于她自己
No. Um, I'm saying this is about her.
这是关于她的成长
It's--it's about her growing up.
如果我有台时光机你知道我会做什么吗
You know what I'd do if I had a time machine?
我会回去...
I'd go back to...
再次经历那些瞬间
relive all those moments.
牵着她的小手
You know, holding her tiny hand,
让她骑在我的肩膀上
putting her up on my shoulders.
我只是
Just...
我不敢相信那些时光一去不复返了
I can't believe those times are gone.
我知道  卡塞尔  但你也要想想
I know, Castle, but think about
你所憧憬的那些美好时光
all of the great times that you have to look forward to
关于她的未来还有我们的
in her future a-and in ours.
是啊  假设有未来的话
Yeah, assuming there is a future.
如果道尔是对的  也许未来根本不存在
If Doyle's right, there may not even be one.
拜托  卡塞尔
Oh, come on, castle.
看看这个
Look at this.
是一篇关于试图引爆炸弹的文章
It's an article on the attempted bombing.
看看图片
Look at the picture.
那是马尔科姆·威克福德  萨娜的继兄
That's Malcolm Wickfield, Shauna's stepbrother.
他当时在会议上
He was at the conference?
他不仅在会议上
He wasn't just at the conference.
他是发言人之一
He was one of the speakers.
威克福德的地址是未公开的
Wickfield's address was unlisted.
你得从警局才拿得到
You had to get it from central.
这就是沃德想从萨娜口中得到的东西
That's what Ward wanted from Shauna?
为了找到她的继兄吗
To find her stepbrother?
他要去杀威克福德
He's going after Wickfield.
纽约警察局  凶杀组的
N.Y.P.D. Homicide.
发生什么事了
What happened?
他妻子说有人出现在门口
Wife said some guy just showed up at the door
袭击了他
and attacked him.
把他往死里打然后拧断了他的脖子
He beat the hell out of him then broke his neck.
没错  就是他
Yes. That's him.
怎么回事
So what happened?
我们当时一起玩填字游戏
We were, uh, doing a crossword puzzle together,
然后  门铃响了
and... the doorbell rang,
之后马尔科姆去开门  那人  就
And when Malcolm answered it, that man, he--
抓住他的脖子
He grabbed him by the neck
然后硬拉着他进了客厅
and he dragged him into the living room
然后他不停喊"那个孩子在哪
and he--he kept yelling, "Where's the child?
怎么找到那个孩子"
H-how can I find the child?"
-什么孩子  -我们不知道
- What child? - We didn't know.
我们告诉他我们不知道  我们没有孩子
We told him we didn't know. We don't have any children.
我打电话报警  当他听到警笛声
I called 9-1-1, and when he heard the sirens,
他就...他就杀了马尔科姆
That's when he... he killed Malcolm.
警察进来之前他已经逃跑了
He--he ran out before they arrived.
威克福德夫人  你丈夫到底是从事什么工作
Mrs. Wickfield, what exactly did your husband do?
他是个理论物理学家
He was a theoretical physicist.
他试图去隔离新能源
He was trying to isolate new energy sources.
为什么有人会把他作为目标呢
Why would anyone target him for that?
因为有人认为他的
Because some people thought that his--
他的实验很危险
His experiments were dangerous,
认为他会...制造一个黑洞
That somehow he was gonna... create a black hole
那会吞没整个地球
That was gonna swallow the earth.
当然  这些都是胡扯
Of course, it was-- it was all nonsense.
这项研究非常令人兴奋
Well, the work is very exciting.
但是目前  都只是理论上的
But right now it's all theoretical.
我们的研究呈现的
What our research really offers
是一个了解宇宙的全新方式
is an entirely new way of looking at the universe.
改变人们了解宇宙的方法
Changing the way people see the universe?
他这种人要是死了
That's exactly the kind of person
绝对能改变未来
whose death could alter the future.
他这种人也刚好是沃德这种疯狂反科学主义者
It's also the kind of person that a crazy anti-science nut
会纠结的对象
like Ward would fixate on.
也就是说会议上的
Which means any of the other speakers
其他发言人有可能是下一个目标
at that conference could be next.
只不过他现在在找一个孩子
Except now he's looking for a child.
和会议主办方联系
Okay, contact the conference organizers.
拿到出席的所有人的名字
Get names of everyone that attended.
看看名单里有没有孩子
Let's see if there are any children on that list.
这家伙会再杀人的
This guy's gonna kill again,
而我们对他一无所知
and we don't know anything about him.
我发现了了解他的人
I may have found someone who does.
那个据称与沃德有联系的环保组织
That eco group that Ward was supposedly a part of?
之后组织解散了  但那时的领导者
Well, it's since disbanded, but its leader at the time
是一个叫杰克·哈斯汀的家伙
was a guy named Jack Hastings.
他现在是一个环境方面的著作者
He's an environmental author now,
而他的新书叫《地球尽头》
and his new book, "Our Earth's End,"
是关于即将到来的生态灾害
It's about the coming eco disasters
以及人类的毁灭
and the destruction of the human race.
如果你想获知未来
If you want to know the future,
来看看这些事实
look at the facts.
在不到35年内  石油
In less than 35 years, we'll have no gas,
煤和铀燃料将消耗殆尽
no coal, and no uranium left.
随着能源减少  和全球变暖引起的
As our energy resources dwindle and needs rise
需求上升
due to global warming,
资源稀缺将不可避免地引发
scarcity will spark the inevitable--
一场血腥的世界大战
a massive, bloody world war,
-大概在未来20年内  -血腥的能源大战
- probably within the next 20 years... - Massive, bloody energy wars?
就像道尔描述的那样
Just like Doyle described.
考虑到地球已经危在旦夕
Given how compromised our planet already is,
人类还能幸存吗
will the human race survive?
谢谢
Thank you.
我认识加瑞特·沃德
Yeah, I knew Garrett Ward.
一开始他来找我们  说的话句句在理
When he first came to us, he said all the right things--
说石油和煤炭巨头在破坏我们的环境
How big oil and coal were destroying our environment.
他甚至帮我策划能源大会的静坐抗议
He even helped me plan that sit-in on the energy conference.
几周之后  他显然对环境
After a few weeks, it became obvious
没那么在意了
he didn't care about the environment.
当他因为那颗炸弹被抓  我们才明白原因
When he was caught with that bomb, we realized why.
他是在利用你混进大会
He was using you to get into the conference.
你对他这个人有什么了解
So how well did you know him personally?
足以确信他是个疯子
Well, enough to know he was nuts.
怎么说
How so?
他疑神疑鬼
He was... paranoid.
总是时刻留心  紧张兮兮的
He was always looking over his shoulder.
他还会说起未来的事
And he'd say things about the future,
说那些战争浩劫导致的动乱
messed-up things about apocalyptic wars
说人类多么需要清洗
and how the human race needed to be cleansed.
这太诡异了
It was pretty creepy.
有点像你刚才做的某些预测
Kind of like some of the predictions you just made?
不  这不一样
No. This was different.
沃德说起时  像是现实一样
Ward talked about it like it was real,
像是已经发生的事
like it had already happened.
他有没有对你说过一个小孩
Did he ever say anything to you about a child?
我不记得说过
Not that I recall.
那这个人呢
What about this guy?
你认识他吗
You recognize him?
抱歉
Sorry.
你知道他跟什么人往来密切
Do you know if there was anyone that he was close to,
或是谁会知道他的下落吗
anyone who would know how to find him?
自从他因为那颗炸弹进了监狱
He burned every bridge he had
大家都跟他断绝了来往
when he walked in with that bomb.
但如果你们要找他
But if you're looking for him,
我会去东河发电站试试
I'd try the East River Power Plant.
六年前他就住在那儿
That's where he was living six years ago.
他说住在电磁场覆盖的区域
He said, uh, the electromagnetic field
政府更不容易找到他
made it harder for the government to find him.
我说过  这人是个疯子
I told you, the guy was crazy.
这里2010年就关闭了
This place shut down in 2010.
你真觉得他会回到这儿
You really think he'd come back here?
你要是太害怕  可以在车里等
You can stay in the car if you're too scared.
我一个人
Alone?
在一座废弃的发电站  不了  多谢
At an abandoned power plant? No, thank you.
也许我们应该在婚誓里加几句
Maybe we should put something in our vows
跟彼此进入诡异的地方应该怎么办
about following each other into creepy places.
我只是说  能源战争
Look, I'm just saying-- energy wars,
来自未来的士兵
a soldier from the future--
一切都支持了道尔的说法
Everything seems to support Doyle's story.
你难道不为这一切觉得纳闷吗
Aren't you weirded out by all this?
我为什么要觉得纳闷
Why would I be weirded out?
沃德只是又一个有妄想症的精神分裂者
Ward's just another paranoid schizophrenic,
跟泰德·卡辛斯基[前文提到的炸弹客]
No different than Ted Kaczynski
或者马克·大卫·查普曼没什么不同
Mark David Chapman.
那你怎么解释道尔说的那些
Then how do you explain Doyle?
他大概是深陷在自己幻想中的又一个疯子
Well, probably another crazy who got caught up in his delusion.
他和沃德一定认识对方
He and Ward must know each other somehow.
卡塞尔
Castle.
有人来过这里
Someone's been here.
不要  不要
Don't--don't--
是他  走吧
It's him. Come on.
-你要去哪儿  -呼叫援助
- Where are you going? - Call for backup.
好主意
Good idea.
该死
Damn it.
贝克特
Beckett?
好了
Okay.
你是怎么找到我们的
How'd you find us?
我没有  我是在跟踪沃德
I didn't. I was tracking Ward.
你说过你不认识他  但他认出了你
You said you didn't know him, but he recognized you.
不  他是认出了这个  好吗
Well, no, he recognized this, okay?
这是一个追踪警示灯
This is a tracking beacon.
-什么  -我只需要用这个碰到他
- A what? - All I have to do is touch him with it,
我们的科学家就能把他拉回去
and our scientists can pull him right back.
放下武器  举起手来
Drop your weapon. Hands in the air.
好吧  别紧张
Okay. Easy.
好吧  警探
Okay. Detective,
真的没必要举枪
the gun is really not necessary.
没必要才怪
The hell it isn't.
你是怎么逃出拘留室的
How did you get out of holding?
你怎么会牵涉其中
And how are you involved?
你知道原因
You know how.
你只是不愿意相信我  但请相信我
You just don't want to believe me, but trust me,
警探
Detective,
我们是一边的
we're on the same side.
你有意识到是我救了你  对吧
You do realize I just saved your life, right?
是啊  我是贝克特警探
Yeah, this is Detective Beckett.
我有一个嫌疑犯在逃
I've got a suspect at large.
我需要对这片区域彻底排查
I'm gonna need patrol sweeps of the area
还要一队鉴证组到现场来
along with a full C.S.U. Team at the scene.
她可真是迷人
Real charmer, that one.
我不敢相信你娶了她
I can't believe you marry her.
-你怎么知道我娶了她  -你书封面上写的
- How did you know I marry her? - One of your book jackets.
"理查德·卡塞尔和他的妻子贝克特议员
You know, "Richard Castle lives in New York
以及他们的三个孩子  住在纽约"
with his wife, Senator Beckett, and their three children."
-参议员  -三个孩子
- Senator? - Three kids?
是啊是啊  我自己也有点
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. It was kind of hard for me
不敢相信  鉴于你们之间发生的
to believe myself, given all the crazy stuff
-那些疯狂的事  -疯狂的事  什么事
- that goes on between you along the way. - Crazy stuff? What stuff?
你开什么玩笑  她...
Are you kidding me? She--
我再打给你
I'll call you back.
不  我不该说的  我不该说
No, I shouldn't say. I shouldn't say.
不过我可以告诉你  我真的很高兴
I can tell you, thought, that I'm really glad
你不再写那些愚蠢的悬疑小说了
you stopped writing those stupid mystery books, okay?
因为你的严肃文学要好看多了
Because your serious literature is so much better.
我写了严肃文学  贝克特  你听见了吗
I write serious literature? Beckett, you hear that?
是的  我听见了
Yeah, I heard.
我还是梦境国的总统呢
And I'm the president of fantasyland.
不  其实是参议员
No, it was--it was senator, actually.
是议员  前提是沃德
It was... Senator, but not if ward
没有改变未来  你明白吗
changes the future, do you understand me?
明白  但是威克福德死了
Yeah, but didn't the time stream already change
时间流不是已经改变了
with Wickfield's murder?
不  威克福德的死只是小干扰
No, no, Wickfield's death was a--was a minor disruption.
但是他所做的一切
But all the work he was doing...
都无关紧要
Never amounted to anything.
他对历史无足轻重
Nah, he wound up a footnote in history.
根据我们的计算  大事件
According to our calculation, the big event,
无论是什么  都还没发生
Whatever it is, it hasn't happened yet.
-那为什么沃德在找他  -我也不知道
- Then why was Ward after him?- I don't know.
你说他在找一个孩子  对吧
You--you said he was looking for a child, right?
-他有  -卡塞尔
- Well, he had-- -Castle!
他是我们嫌犯
He's our suspect.
能麻烦你别和他讨论案子的细节吗
Could you please not discuss details of our with him?
你可以过来帮我
Maybe you could come over here and help me
看看这些东西  没准能找到线索
look through this stuff. We might find a clue...
知道沃德下一个被害者是谁
as to who Ward's next victim's gonna be.
仅供参考
For your information,
我没有讨论案子的细节
I wasn't sharing details of the case.
我在糊弄他看看他知道什么
I was playing into his delusion to see what he knew.
看  这是一封旧信的照片
Look at this. This is a photograph of an old letter
收信人是马尔科姆·威克福德
addressed to Malcolm Wickfield.
时间是六年前
It's dated six years ago.
像是一个高中生
Looks like it's from a high school student
请求他在能源大会上发言
asking to see him speak at that energy conference.
沃德怎么会有这个
Why would Ward have this?
不知道  这只是第一页
I don't know. It's only the first page,
没有名字  没有签名
but there's no name or signature.
看沃德圈出的词
But look at the words Ward circled.
"布鲁克林"  "PS311"
"Brooklyn," "P.S. 311," "State award
"州政府去年嘉奖了我的物理项目"
last year for my physics project."
每一个都是写信人的线索
Each one's a clue as to the letter writer's identity.
沃德一定在找他
Ward must have been after him.
你觉得这是沃德要找的孩子吗
Do you think this is the child that Ward is looking for?
道尔先生  你知道他是谁吗
Mr. Doyle... do you know who he is?
不  我以前从没见过他
No, no, I've never seen him before.
但如果沃德在找他  一定是有原因的
But if Ward's targeting him, there must be a reason.
沃德为什么要找个高中生呢
Why would Ward be after a high school student?
我也不知道  但我们得先找到他
I don't know. But we gotta find him first.
但是没名字  只有这些线索
Yeah, but no name, and only these clues to go on?
要花数天
It could take days.
我能提个议吗
Hey, could I make a suggestion?
你知道  沃德
Ward, you know,
在根据信件的照片查找  对吗
he was working off of a photo of the letter, right?
或许简单点的方法是问问
So perhaps the easier path is to ask,
原件在哪
where's the original?
上面一定有这孩子的名字和地址
It's bound to have the kid's name and address.
六年前的信
A letter from six years ago.
好消息是天才都不爱扔东西
Good thing most geniuses are pack rats.
我一直劝他把这些扔出去
I kept trying to get him to throw some of this stuff out,
但是他从不  让我再看一眼照片
But he never would. Uh, let me see that picture again.
你确定以前没看见过这孩子
You sure you've never seen the kid before?
没有  但马尔科姆总是很鼓励学生
No, but, uh, Malcolm was very encouraging to students,
有可能他认识这孩子
so it's a possibility that he knew him.
等等
Wait a minute.
这里
Here.
就是它
That's it.
写信人是个叫保罗·杜查尔的孩子
It's written by some kid named Paul Deschile.
等等  不是
Wait a second. No.
不是蒂希尔
That's not "De-shiel." Um...
是 杜查尔
It's "Duh-child."
他不是在找"孩子"
He wasn't looking for "the child,"
而是在找"杜查尔"[音似]
he was looking for Deschile.
保罗·杜查尔是谁
Who the hell's Paul Deschile?
他是个21岁  在哈德森大学
He's a 21-year-old student at Hudson
在读理论物理的博士后
getting his post-doc in theoretical physics.
对他进行保护性拘留
All right, get him into protective custody.
他这学期不在学校
He's on leave this semester.
校方也不知道他在哪
The university has no idea where he is.
还在找他的父母
Still trying to look for his parents,
-他们几年前搬去了别的州  -探长  就是他
- but they moved out of state a few years ago. - Detective, It's him!
杜查尔  你知道他
Deschile. You know him?
我当然知道他  每个人都知道他
Of course I know him. Everyone knows him.
天啊  要是他死了
Oh, man, if-- if he's killed...
好  我一会儿打给你  道尔  坐下
Okay, I'll call you back. Doyle, sit down.
难怪亿万人会死
No wonder billions of people die.
好吧  到底谁是保罗·杜查尔
Okay, who the hell is Paul Deschile?
能源战争  我告诉过你敌方的事
The energy wars, all right? I told you about the other side.
一群法西斯主义者  比纳粹还糟糕
A group of fascists-- they were worse than the nazis.
他们杀的人
Th-they were slaughtering people
有好几百万  好吗
by the tens of thousands, okay?
他们一直在胜利
They were winning.
直到杜查尔和他的团队创造出了能源盾牌
Until Deschile--he and his team, they created an energy shield.
阻止了他们的武器
Okay? It was able to stop their weapons
完全扭转了局面
and completely turn the tide.
探长  听我说
Detective, listen to me!
沃德很明显是为了法西斯而战的
Ward is still obviously fighting for the fascists!
他们试图通过改写历史  获得战争胜利
They're trying to win the war by rewriting history!
如果他杀了杜查尔  就没有能源盾牌了
And if he kills Deschile, there will be no energy shield!
没有能源盾牌  我们就输了
And without that energy shield, we lose that war!
沃德要杀杜查尔
Ward's gonna kill Deschile,
所以数十亿的人才会死
and that is why billions of people die!
行了  你知道么  没时间听你瞎说了
Okay, you know what? We don't have time for this.
-把他拘留起来  -好吧
-Take him to holding, please. - Fine,
我们是没时间了  你对了  好了吧
we don't have time. You're correct, okay?
忘了我说的  忘了时间穿越
Forget everything I said! Forget about time travel!
忘了战争  都不重要
Forget about wars! None of that matters!
重要的是杜查尔  你懂了吗
All that matters is Deschile! You understand me?
你要让他活着  他不能死
You keep him alive! He cannot die!
不  杜查尔  对
No. Deschile. Yeah.
保罗·杜查尔
Paul Deschile.
不  等等  别让我等着
No, wait, please don't-- don't put me on hold.
-有消息了  -埃斯波西托
- Anything? - Esposito
在俄勒冈找了他父母
got ahold of his parents in Oregon.
他们觉得他在城里的一个朋友家
They think he's staying with a friend in the city,
我正在联系他
which is who I'm holding for now.
你不会觉得这是真的吧
You don't think any of this could possibly be real, do you?
我也不知道  卡塞尔
I don't know, Castle,
但我不想让这个孩子死
but I have no intention of letting this kid die.
你好  我是纽约警局凯特·贝克特探长
Yes. Hi. This is Detective Kate Beckett, N.Y.P.D.
我在试图联系保罗·杜查尔
I'm trying to get ahold of a Paul Deschile.
哪里
Where?
他在天文馆
He's at the planetarium.
等等  你也告诉另一个人了
Wait, just like you told what other guy?
你还告诉谁了
Who else did you tell?
沃德知道了
Ward knows.
天文馆在上城区
Planetarium's all the way uptown.
我们赶不及了
We'll never get there in time.
宇宙是浩渺而壮丽的
The cosmos is vast and glorious--
奇妙得超乎我们的想象
More wondrous than we can fathom.
它让我们惊叹不已  点亮我们的想象
It takes our breath away and ignites our imagination.
它是时间的本质
It is the essence of time itself--
过去  现在  未来
The past, the present, and the future.
它似乎就是无法解开的谜团
It's an enigma seemingly impossible to grasp,
然而我们还是去探寻它的神秘
and yet we pursue its mysteries.
我们勇敢地走出去  试图了解
We dare to reach out to understand
漩涡状星系  爆发星
swirling galaxies, exploding stars...
不许动
Freeze!
想都别想
Don't even think about it!
纽约警局  举起你的手
N.Y.P.D.! Let me see your hands right now!
他有刀
Knife!
你还好吗  小子
You okay, kid?
为什么要杀威克福德
Why Wickfield?
为什么要杀杜查尔
Why deschile?
你想达到什么目的
What were you hoping to accomplish?
他是谁
Who is that man?
在发电厂  你看到他就跑掉了  为什么
You ran from him at the power plant. Why?
沃德先生  2007年之前系统里没有你的记录
Mr. Ward, there is no record of you before 2007.
你从哪来的
Where are you from?
好吧  沃德
Okay, Ward.
不管你认为你在干什么
Whatever you thought you were doing...
都结束了
It's over.
他说什么了
What'd he say?
-什么都没说  -没有末日景象
- Nothing. - No apocalyptic visions,
没有对即将到来的灾难的噩梦般警告吗
no nightmarish warnings of dire things to come?
不管他有什么妄想
Whatever delusions he has in his head,
他都不打算告诉别人
he is keeping them to himself.
如果道尔说的都是假的
Well, if nothing Doyle said was true,
沃德为什么想对杜查尔下杀手
why else would Ward target Deschile?
我们能回答这个问题
I think we can answer that.
六年前  在一个能源会议上  是我
I'm the one who alerted security to Ward's behavior
向安保警告了沃德的行为
at the energy conference six years ago.
他们因为我而阻止了他
They stopped him because of me.
看起来一切都是为了报仇
It looks like this was all just about revenge.
我只是对威克福德博士为此丧命而感到抱歉
I'm just sorry it cost Dr. Wickfield his life.
知道吗  他在那次会议上的发言
You know, the talk he gave at that conference
改变了我的世界  如果不是他
rocked my world, and if it wasn't for him,
我可能在做完全不同的事情
I'd probably be doing something completely different with my life.
走吧  我送你出去
Come on, man. I'll walk you out.
看来  还是有一个简单合理的解释的
So, there is a simple explanation after all.
是的  现在我们知道沃德为什么要炸会议现场了
Yes. Now we know why Ward tried to bomb that conference--
要杀掉杜查尔
To kill Deschile.
你看  在未来  已经成名了的杜查尔
You see, in the future, when the famous Deschile
会接受采访  他会提到一切开始的地方
will give interviews, he'll say that's where it all started.
巧合的是  沃德也会知道具体在哪里
Consequently, Ward will know exactly where--
在什么时候  找到他
and when--to find him.
你是想把我逼疯  是吧
You're trying to drive me crazy, aren't you?
很显然已经逼疯了  如果我们育有三个孩子的话
Well, apparently I already do, if we end up with three kids.
想知道他们的名字吗
Would you like to know their names?
-想  -不想
- Yes. - No!
道尔  你怎么被放出来了
Doyle? What are you doing out?
你说我有权利请律师
Well, you said that I had the right to an attorney,
律师说你不能再把我关在这了
and he said that you couldn't keep me anymore.
-你的心理评估呢  -得了吧  你在开玩笑吗
- What about your psych eval? - Oh, please. Are you kidding me?
我轻松通过有没有
I passed that with flying colors.
不过你真该听听从我嘴里说出的那些话
But you should have heard the crazy stuff coming out of my mouth.
在丹佛长大  中产家庭
Growing up in Denver, middle-class family.
真是的  我好久没说那么多谎话了
I mean, I haven't lied that much in years.
-但是  -哎呦  探长  别烦躁
- But I-- -  Now, now, Detective, don't be upset.
因为你  亿万人活了下来
Because of you, billions of people are alive.
因为你  未来的几代人是安全的
Because of you, future generations are safe.
我才不管这些  道尔
I don't care what you say, Doyle.
你和沃德之间是有联系的
There's a connection between you and Ward,
而且这联系跟时间旅行没有关系
and it has nothing to do with time travel.
我会找到的
And I'm gonna find out what it is.
好吧  祝你好运
Okay. Good luck.
因为在昨天之前  我都没见过沃德
Because before yesterday, I had never even met Ward.
那可不是真话
That's not entirely true.
我翻看沃德的监禁档案
I went back through Ward's incarceration file.
审判前  他在州政府的批准下
Before his trial, he spent two weeks
在一个精神科病房待了两周  被心理评估
in a psychiatric ward being evaluated by the state.
隔壁是另一位患者  无名氏
In the next room was another patient, a john doe.
我调出了他的照片
I had them pull his photo.
找到联系了
And there's the connection.
不不不  那太扯了
No, no, no. That-- that's--that's ridiculous.
因为我从来没……
Because I have never, ever...
天啊  太机智了
Oh, wow, that's really clever.
什么  哪里机智了
What? What's clever?
那是我
That's me.
但是我还没干那些事呢
Right? But I-I haven't done it yet.
你看不出吗
Don't you see?
现在他们知道沃德是谁  在哪
Now that they know who Ward is and where he's gonna be...
他们会把我派回去  与他接触
They're gonna send me back to make contact with him,
找出他的雇主  查出他们的其他计划
find out who he works for, if they're planning anything else.
堪称完美
It's perfect.
呃  我没有多少时间了
Oh, wow. Uh, I don't have much time left.
怎么说好呢  20年后见
Um... I don't know. See you in 20 years.
是我的幻觉  还是这一切都说得通啊
Is it--is it just me, or does that make sense?
是你的幻觉
No, it's just you.
他忘拿自己的小玩意了
Ooh, he forgot his little doohickey there.
怎么了
Hey. So what happened?
没赶上他
Missed him.
你猜怎么着
You know what?
在这样一个案子后  一个暖和舒适的泡澡
After a case like this one, I think a warm and cozy bath
会在我的未来发生
is in my future.
今晚给你打电话
Talk to you tonight?
好
Sounds good.
你真的要这么做
You're really doing this?
是的
I am.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
你认为我在犯了一个大错
You're thinking I'm making a huge mistake.
如果我的想法是对的呢
What if you are?
这不是一件你可以倒回去重做的事
This isn't something you can just go back and undo.
你要不再等一年
Why don't you wait a year, okay?
搬到宿舍
Move into the dorms.
我确信派可以照顾他自己
I'm sure Pi can take care of himself.
如果一年后  你还是想跟他同居
And if after a year you still want to move in together,
我绝不会反对
I won't say a word.
你会
Yes, you will.
我不知道这会有什么结果
I don't know how this is gonna turn out, dad.
我们都不知道
None of us do.
但这是我的生活  我的未来
But it's my life, my future.
我得自己去发现
I have to find out for myself.
你总说家里谁最聪明来着
Who are you always saying is the smart one in the family?
你
You.
爸  我知道我在做什么
Dad, I know what I'm doing.
没事的
It'll be okay.
孩子长大得太快了
Too soon.